No need to cry your heart out over this.
‫لا تبك بسبب هذا.‬
You're okay.
‫أنت بخير.‬
Daddy will be coming in soon. Go wait inside, okay?
‫سيلحق بك والدك إلى الداخل سريعًا.‬ ‫ادخل وانتظرني.‬
There, there. It's okay.
‫اهدأ. لا بأس.‬
Seo-ha.
‫"سو ها".‬
How did you get all the way here?
‫كيف وصلت إلى هنا؟‬
Does your mom know you're here?
‫هل تعرف أمك أنك هنا؟‬
Is she doing okay?
‫هل هي بخير؟‬
Mom's doing fine.
‫أمي بخير.‬
I think she might be getting married to someone who treats her well.
‫أظن أنها ستتزوج بشخص يحسن معاملتها.‬
And you?
‫ماذا عنك؟‬
Are you okay?
‫هل أنت بخير؟‬
Does he treat you well too?
‫هل يحسن معاملتك أيضًا؟‬
He's a much better person than you, Dad.
‫إنه أفضل منك بكثير يا أبي.‬
He treats me well too.
‫ويحسن معاملتي أيضًا.‬
Like a real daughter.
‫كأنني ابنته الحقيقية.‬
Then why did you come here?
‫إذًا لماذا أتيت إلى هنا؟‬
To see how you are doing.
‫لأتفقّد أحوالك.‬
To see for myself.
‫لأرى بنفسي.‬
Dad, what are you doing over there?
‫ماذا تفعل هناك يا أبي؟‬
Nothing special. I'm coming in now.
‫لا شيء مهم. أنا قادم.‬
You'd better go back now.
‫من الأفضل أن تعودي الآن.‬
And…
‫و…‬
please don't do this again.
‫لا تفعلي هذا مجددًا من فضلك.‬
Showing up here unannounced
‫حضورك إلى هنا فجأة‬
is awkward for both of us.
‫مربك لكلينا.‬
Goodness, Professor Yoon!
‫عجبًا يا أستاذة "يون"!‬
What brings you here? You didn't even call.
‫لماذا أتيت؟ لم تتصلي حتى.‬
You've had a drink too?
‫هل شربت أيضًا؟‬
Anyway, I'm glad you're here. I have something to ask you.
‫في أي حال، يسعدني حضورك.‬ ‫أريد أن أطلب منك شيئًا.‬
Take a look at these.
‫انظري إلى هذه.‬
These are the drafts for my daughter's wedding invitation--
‫هذه مسودات للدعوة إلى زفاف ابنتي…‬
Sir, I came here to talk to you.
‫سيدي، أتيت لأتحدث إليك.‬
Yes, of course. We should talk.
‫نعم، طبعًا. يجب أن نتحدث.‬
Yes.
‫نعم.‬
You came to talk about what happened to Hong-sik, right?
‫أتيت لتتحدثي إليّ‬ ‫بشأن ما أصاب "هونغ سيك"، صحيح؟‬
Yes.
‫نعم.‬
How dare that son of a bitch mess with my boy?
‫كيف يجرؤ ذاك السافل على العبث مع صديقي؟‬
I cared so much for Hong-sik!
‫كان "هونغ سيك" عزيزًا على قلبي.‬
And the killer set him on fire, as if shooting him dead wasn't enough?
‫والقاتل أحرقه،‬ ‫كأن إطلاق النار عليه وقتله لم يكن كافيًا.‬
I heard that
‫سمعت‬
the culprit is your half-brother.
‫أن القاتل هو أخوك غير الشقيق.‬
He's lucky that the cops got to him first.
‫من حسن حظه أن الشرطة اعتقلته أولًا.‬
If it were me, I would've made sure that he never walked again.
‫لو أن الأمر بيدي،‬ ‫لحرصت على ألّا يعيش ليرى يومًا آخر.‬
Anyway,
‫في أي حال،‬
we should get on with the deal for this building, shouldn't we?
‫يجب أن نمضي في صفقة بيع المبنى، أليس كذلك؟‬
Yes, about that, as you already know, the inheritance hasn't been resolved yet.
‫بلى. بالنسبة إلى ذلك، كما تعلم،‬
Still?
‫حتى الآن؟‬
That bastard has been preparing a paternity suit
‫ذاك الوغد يعدّ قضية إثبات أبوة‬
to claim a right to the burial ground.
‫للمطالبة بحقه في أرض المقابر.‬
How can he do that if he's convicted? That won't be an issue at all.
‫كيف يفعل هذا إن كان محكومًا؟‬ ‫لن تكون هذه مشكلة.‬
No, unfortunately not. That bastard
‫لا، للأسف لا. ذاك الوغد‬
keeps denying that he killed anyone.
‫ينكر باستمرار أنه قتل أي أحد.‬
Well, the police must have some kind of evidence if they're holding him.
‫لا بد أن الشرطة تملك دليلًا ما‬ ‫إن كانوا يعتقلونه.‬
Don't worry, Ms. Yoon.
‫لا تقلقي يا سيدة "يون".‬
But the thing is, they don't have any evidence yet.
‫لكن ليس لديهم أي دليل بعد.‬
What?
‫ماذا؟‬
Are you telling me that he might walk if he doesn't confess?
‫أتقولين إنه قد يخرج من السجن إن لم يعترف؟‬
Then who the fuck killed Hong-sik?
‫إذًا من قتل "هونغ سيك"؟‬
How can they release a murder suspect like that?
‫كيف يطلقون سراح مشتبه به بهذه البساطة؟‬
That's what I'm trying to tell you.
‫هذا ما أحاول أن أخبرك إياه.‬
If the police release him, I can't do anything about it.
‫إذا أطلقت الشرطة سراحه،‬ ‫لا يمكنني أن أفعل أي شيء بشأن ذلك.‬
Then I won't be receiving the inheritance for a while,
‫وحينها لن أستلم الميراث في وقت قريب،‬
which means I can't buy your building.
‫مما يعني أنه لا يمكنني أن أشتري مبناك.‬
Fucking hell! That's no good!
‫اللعنة! هذا ليس جيدًا!‬
What's wrong with those damned cops?
‫ما مشكلة هؤلاء الشرطيين اللعينين؟‬
Goddamn it!
‫بئسًا!‬
Shit.
‫تبًا!‬
DETECTIVE PARK SANG-MIN
‫"المحقق (سانغ مين بارك)"‬
-Yes? -Ms. Yoon.
‫- نعم؟‬ ‫- سيدة "يون".‬
Yes.
‫نعم.‬
This is Detective Park from Namil Police Station.
‫أنا المحقق "بارك" من قسم شرطة "ناميل".‬
Regarding the recent incident with the blood,
‫بالنسبة إلى الحادث الأخير المرتبط بالدماء،‬
you should file a complaint against Kim.
‫يجب أن تقدّمي شكوى بحق "كيم".‬
I'm sure he's the culprit.
‫أنا متأكد من أنه الفاعل.‬
You haven't found any evidence, have you?
‫ألم تجدوا أي أدلة بعد؟‬
Give us a bit more time.
‫امنحينا المزيد من الوقت.‬
As long as we have reason to hold him, we will be able to find solid evidence.
‫ما دام لدينا سبب لاعتقاله،‬ ‫فسنجد أدلة دامغة.‬
Please trust us and proceed with your complaint.
‫ثقي بناء رجاءً وقدّمي الدعوى.‬
-I'm not going to file a complaint. -Ms. Yoon--
‫- لن أتقدم بشكوى.‬ ‫- يا سيدة "يون"…‬
If that guy walks,
‫إن خرج هذا الرجل من السجن،‬
I'll arrange for a lawyer friend of mine
‫سأطلب من محام صديق لي‬
to scare him a little
‫أن يخيفه قليلًا‬
and talk some legal sense into him to secure a signed agreement.
‫ويقنعه بالمنطق القانوني ليوقّع اتفاقًا.‬
Don't you worry.
‫لا تقلقي.‬
Hong-sik told me
‫أخبرني "هونغ سيك"‬
that your father lived with that half-brother of yours.
‫أن والدك كان يعيش مع أخيك غير الشقيق.‬
That bastard stole your father's love
‫سرق ذاك السافل محبة أبيك‬
and even killed your husband.
‫وقتل زوجك.‬
Are you going to let him take half your inheritance?
‫هل ستدعينه يأخذ نصف ميراثك؟‬
If it were me, I'd never let that shit happen.
‫لو أن الأمر يعود إليّ، لما سمحت بحصول ذلك.‬
So,
‫إذًا…‬
shall we proceed or not?
‫هل نتابع أم لا؟‬
Please do.
‫فلتتابع رجاءً.‬
I'll leave it to you.
‫سأدع الأمر لك.‬
You made the right decision.
‫اتخذت القرار الصائب.‬
You should get that inheritance already and start a new life, right?
‫يجب أن تحصلي على ذاك الميراث‬ ‫وتبدئي حياة جديدة، صحيح؟‬
THE BEQUEATHED
‫"وريثة رفات الأسلاف"‬
CHIEF'S OFFICE
‫"مكتب الرئيس"‬
You said Kim Young-ho was the one!
‫قلت إن "يونغ هو كيم" هو الفاعل.‬
I kissed Prosecutor Kim's ass just to get you that fuckin' warrant,
‫تملقت المدعي العام "كيم"‬ ‫لأؤمّن لك تلك المذكرة،‬
and you screw up once again?
‫لتخفق مجددًا؟‬
Shit!
‫تبًا!‬
LETTER OF RESIGNATION
‫"خطاب استقالة"‬
Hey, what is this?
‫مهلًا، ما هذا؟‬
I'll take responsibility and resign.
‫أتحمّل كامل المسؤولية وأنا أستقيل.‬
I heard they're reducing personnel in our station anyway.
‫سمعت أنكم ستخففون عدد الموظفين‬ ‫في القسم في أي حال.‬
And I'm aware of the rumor about me
‫وأعرف الشائعة السارية‬
getting laid off.
‫بأنني سأُطرد.‬
I can't believe this idiot.
‫لا أصدق هذا الأحمق.‬
Listen, you fool.
‫اسمع يا غبي.‬
Do you think you even deserve to hand in a resignation?
‫هل تظن أنك تستحق أن تقدّم استقالتك؟‬
Damn it.
‫بئسًا.‬
As for the personnel reduction, Choi Sung-jun will be leaving.
‫بالنسبة إلى تقليص عدد الموظفين،‬ ‫سيغادر "سونغ جون تشوي".‬
Sir?
‫عفوًا؟‬
Choi Sung-jun will be quitting.
‫"سونغ جون تشوي" سيستقيل.‬
He came to see me last night. The matter has been settled.
‫أتى ليراني البارحة وسُويت المسألة.‬
What you should do is sweet-talk him
‫عليك أن تقنعه بكلّ لطف‬
into solving this case before he leaves.
‫بأن يحلّ هذه القضية قبل أن يغادر.‬
Got it?
‫مفهوم؟‬
LANDLORD CHOI TAE-SEONG
‫"مالك المبنى (تاي سونغ تشوي)"‬
HE JUST MET KIM YOUNG-HO DON'T WORRY TOO MUCH
‫"التقى (يونغ هو كيم) للتو. لا تقلقي كثيرًا"‬
JUST MAKE YOURSELF AN ALIBI
‫"جدي لنفسك حجة غياب"‬
OKAY, THANK YOU
‫"حسنًا، شكرًا"‬
-Fuck! -Grab this asshole!
‫- اللعنة!‬ ‫- أمسكا بهذا الوغد!‬
Stay put, you son of a bitch!
‫لا تتحرك أيها السافل!‬
-Fuckin' bastard! -Asshole!
‫- سافل لعين!‬ ‫- حقير!‬
You son of a bitch!
‫أيها السافل!‬
-Hey. -Fuck you, son of a bitch!
‫- مهلًا.‬ ‫- تبًا لك أيها الوغد!‬
Keep still, asshole!
‫لا تتحرك يا نذل!‬
Don't move!
‫لا تتحرك!‬
NAMIL POLICE STATION
‫"قسم شرطة (ناميل)"‬
In my opinion, Kim Young-ho is not the culprit.
‫برأيي، "يونغ هو كيم" ليس القاتل.‬
I don't get why Detective Park is so obsessed with him.
‫لا أفهم لما المحقق "بارك" مهووس به.‬
Hello, sir.
‫مرحبًا يا سيدي.‬
What are you all doing right now? I heard Kim Young-ho was released.
‫ماذا تفعلون الآن؟‬ ‫سمعت أنه أُطلق سراح "يونغ هو كيم".‬
Did you organize protection?
‫هل اتخذتم تدابير للحماية؟‬
-No. -What? What about Yoon Seo-ha?
‫- لا.‬ ‫- ماذا؟ ماذا عن "سو ها يون"؟‬
I mean, Detective Park says we don't need to look out for her.
‫قال المحقق "بارك" إنه ليس علينا أن نحميها.‬
He just wants us to find evidence on Kim.
‫يريدنا أن نجد أدلة تدين "كيم".‬
We're also frustrated about who we should listen to!
‫نحن أيضًا مستاؤون‬ ‫لأننا لا نعرف أوامر من ننفذ.‬
Someone else is the perpetrator.
‫القاتل شخص آخر.‬
-They are both in danger right now. -What?
‫- كلاهما في خطر الآن.‬ ‫- ماذا؟‬
Either of them could be the next victim!
‫قد يكون أي منهما الضحية التالية!‬
Track down their locations and stay on them.
‫تعقبوا موقعيهما وراقبوهما.‬
-Now! -Yes, sir. Let's go, guys!
‫- الآن!‬ ‫- نعم يا سيدي. لنذهب يا رفاق!‬
ATTORNEY KIM JUNG-TAE
‫"المحامي (جونغ تاي كيم)"‬
Hey, asshole. Stay still.
‫أيها الحقير! لا تتحرك.‬
Get a hold of yourself, fucker!
‫تمالك نفسك أيها اللعين!‬
Mom…
‫أمي…‬
-Hey. -Mom!
‫- مهلًا.‬ ‫- أمي!‬
-Hey, bring him here if he's awake. -Yes, sir!
‫- أحضروه إلى هنا إن كان مستيقظًا.‬ ‫- نعم يا سيدي.‬
Get up, asshole.
‫انهض أيها الوغد.‬
Up, you son of a bitch!
‫انهض أيها السافل!‬
Who are you people?
‫من أنتم؟‬
Mr. Kim, you're not hurt, are you?
‫يا سيد "كيم"، لم تتعرض لأذى، صحيح؟‬
We're not bad guys. I'm a lawyer.
‫لسنا أشرارًا. أنا محام.‬
We're not doing this because we have anything against you.
‫لا نفعل هذا لأننا نملك أي شيء يدينك.‬
We just have business to discuss, so don't get the wrong idea.
‫لكننا نريد أن نناقش معك بعض المسائل‬ ‫فلا تسئ الفهم.‬
There's nothing difficult about this. You see here?
‫لا يُوجد شيء صعب في هذا. أترى هنا؟‬
WITHDRAWAL OF LAWSUIT
‫"سحب الدعوى"‬
We just need your thumbprints. Sign it.
‫نحتاج إلى بصمات أصابعك وحسب. ابصم.‬
-No. -Hurry up.
‫- لا.‬ ‫- أسرع.‬
No!
‫لا!‬
Why the hell are you doing this?
‫لماذا تفعلون هذا بحق الجحيم؟‬
Shut up, dumbass! Grab his thumb!
‫اصمت أيها الغبي! أمسك بإبهامه!‬
Get his thumbprint!
‫خذ بصمة إبهامه.‬
That burial ground belongs to me, you motherfucker!
‫تلك المقبرة لي أيها السافل!‬
What now? What the fuck?
‫ماذا؟ غير معقول!‬
Hey, wait a minute!
‫مهلًا، انتظر لحظة!‬
Hey, asshole!
‫أيها النذل!‬
You're asking for it!
‫أنت تطلب العقاب!‬
Hey, get that fucking bastard! Get him, you idiots!
‫أمسكوا بالسافل! أمسكوا به يا أغبياء!‬
Get up, you bastard!
‫انهض أيها الوغد!‬
Son of a bitch!
‫أيها السافل!‬
-Someone catch him! -Motherfucker!
‫- ليمسك به أحد!‬ ‫- السافل!‬
My leg!
‫ساقي!‬
Fuck!
‫اللعنة!‬
-Grab that bastard! -Motherfuckers.
‫- أمسكوا بالوغد!‬ ‫- أيها الأنذال.‬
-Damn it! -Sons of bitches!
‫- تبًا!‬ ‫- أيها السفلة!‬
You fuckin' son of a bitch!
‫أيها السافل اللعين!‬
Hey!
‫مهلًا!‬
Please stop!
‫توقّفوا أرجوكم!‬
-Run down! -What the fuck was that?
‫- انزل!‬ ‫- ما كان ذلك؟‬
What the fuck?
‫ما هذا؟‬
Help me.
‫ساعدني.‬
Please help me!
‫ساعدني رجاءً!‬
Help me, sir.
‫ساعدني يا سيدي.‬
-Sir, please help. -Hey.
‫- سيدي، ساعدني أرجوك.‬ ‫- مهلًا.‬
Hey, get up.
‫أنت! انهض!‬
Fuck. You're with them, aren't you?
‫اللعنة! أنت معهم، أليس كذلك؟‬
Damn! This is gonna be a hassle!
‫تبًا! سيكون هذا متعبًا!‬
Good evening, sir!
‫مساء الخير!‬
You!
‫أنت!‬
Why did you let things get to this?
‫لماذا سمحت للأمور بأن تصل إلى هذا؟‬
Did you get it signed?
‫هل وقّع على المستند؟‬
Not yet, sir. That crazy bastard bit my nose and--
‫ليس بعد يا سيدي.‬ ‫ذلك الوغد المجنون عض أنفي و…‬
I'm sorry, sir.
‫أنا آسف يا سيدي.‬
Motherfucker!
‫سافل!‬
That fucking bastard!
‫ذاك اللعين!‬
Hey!
‫أنت!‬
LANDLORD CHOI TAE-SEONG
‫"مالك المبنى (تاي سونغ تشوي)"‬
-Hey, Ms. Yoon. -Hello.
‫- مرحبًا يا سيدة "يون".‬ ‫- مرحبًا.‬
Did you get the agreement signed?
‫هل وقّع على المستند؟‬
Well, he didn't exactly sign the agreement,
‫لم يوقّع على المستند تحديدًا،‬
but we just have to make sure your half-brother disappears, right?
‫لكن علينا التخلص من أخيك غير الشقيق.‬
Wait, what are you--
‫مهلًا، ما الذي…‬
Well, my position has become quite difficult.
‫في الواقع، أصبح موقفي صعبًا جدًا.‬
But why? Mr. Choi, what happened?
‫لكن لماذا؟ ماذا حدث يا سيد "تشوي"؟‬
This guy seems to be badly hurt.
‫يبدو هذا الرجل مصابًا إصابة خطيرة.‬
What?
‫ماذا؟‬
You just need him to disappear, right?
‫تريدينه أن يختفي وحسب، صحيح؟‬
You said he doesn't have any relatives around.
‫قلت إنه ليس له أي أقارب.‬
It wouldn't be a big deal if he goes away, huh?
‫لن ينزعج أحد إن اختفى، صحيح؟‬
Wait, what do you mean by that?
‫مهلًا، ماذا تقصد بكلامك؟‬
Shit!
‫تبًا!‬
The thing is,
‫في الحقيقة،‬
this kid saw my face.
‫لقد رأى وجهي.‬
If he squeals later on,
‫إذا وشى بنا لاحقًا،‬
that would put you in a tough spot too.
‫فقد يضعك ذلك في موقع حرج أيضًا.‬
Anyway, we'll take good care of things here.
‫في أي حال، سنهتم بالأمور هنا.‬
Just get the contract ready and meet me soon, okay?
‫جهّزي العقد ولنلتق قريبًا، اتفقنا؟‬
Take care of things how?
‫كيف ستهتم بالأمور؟‬
You were just meant to scare him and get his thumbprints!
‫كان يُفترض بكم أن تخيفوه‬ ‫وتحصلوا على بصماته وحسب.‬
Ms. Yoon.
‫يا سيدة "يون".‬
You don't need to worry so much.
‫لا داعي لكلّ هذا القلق.‬
-We're experts at these things! -I'm sorry, but this is just…
‫- نحن خبراء في هذه الأمور!‬ ‫- آسفة، لكن هذا…‬
My kid's wedding is around the corner.
‫زفاف ابنتي قريب جدًا.‬
Do you really think I would mess this up?
‫أحقًا تظنين أنني سأفسد هذه المسألة؟‬
I'll make this go away like it never happened!
‫سأتولى الأمر ولن تحدث أي مشكلة.‬
No, but Mr. Choi--
‫لا، لكن يا سيد "تشوي"…‬
What the hell is he thinking? That stupid son of a bitch.
‫ما الذي يفعله؟ السافل الغبي!‬
Please leave a message after the--
‫يُرجى ترك رسالة بعد…‬
Shit!
‫تبًا!‬
Hey.
‫مرحبًا.‬
Where are all the files on Yoon Myung-gil's acquaintances?
‫أين ملفات معارف "ميونغ غيل يون"؟‬
What's going on?
‫ماذا يجري؟‬
Where is everyone?
‫أين الجميع؟‬
I sent them out to protect Kim Young-ho and Yoon Seo-ha.
‫أرسلتهم لحماية "يونغ هو كيم" و"سو ها يون".‬
Did our team have two leaders from the start?
‫هل في فريقنا قائدان من البداية؟‬
No.
‫لا.‬
You've been the only leader from the beginning.
‫أنت القائد الوحيد من البداية.‬
Sorry about that. It was urgent.
‫أعتذر. كانت المسألة طارئة.‬
Both of them are in danger right now.
‫كلاهما في خطر الآن.‬
There seems to be someone manipulating Kim Young-ho using religion.
‫يبدو أن أحدهم يتلاعب بـ"يونغ هو كيم"‬ ‫عبر استغلال الدين.‬
It might even be his mother--
‫قد تكون أمه…‬
You're really something, man.
‫غير معقول يا رجل!‬
I get that you're so talented,
‫أعرف أنك موهوب جدًا.‬
but stop showing off, for fuck's sake!
‫لكن كفّ عن التباهي بحق السماء!‬
Hey, what's wrong with you?
‫مهلًا، ما خطبك؟‬
Did you tell the chief you're quitting?
‫هل أخبرت الرئيس أنك ستستقيل؟‬
Do you think I'm a joke?
‫هل تظن أنني مهزلة؟‬
Because I'm leading a lame investigation, fixated on Kim Young-ho?
‫لأنني أرأس تحقيقًا واهيًا‬ ‫وأركّز على "يونغ هو كيم"؟‬
No, not just the investigation. I am literally lame.
‫لا، ليس التحقيق وحسب. أنا تافه فعلًا.‬
Sang-min, we don't have time for this crap right now.
‫يا "سانغ مين"،‬ ‫لا وقت لدينا لهذا الهراء الآن.‬
Do you pity me because I'm about to get fired?
‫هل تشفق عليّ لأنني سأُطرد؟‬
"Oh, he's crippled."
‫"إنه معوّق."‬
"How would he get by without a job?" Is this charity work for you?!
‫"كيف سيتدبر أمره من دون وظيفة؟"‬ ‫هل تعتبرني قضية خيرية؟‬
Why are you so freakin' full of yourself, man?
‫لم أنت مغرور لهذه الدرجة؟‬
You bastard.
‫أيها النذل.‬
Cut it out for God's sake!
‫كفّ عن ذلك بحقك!‬
Sang-min, I'm sorry.
‫أنا آسف يا "سانغ مين".‬
Bring it on, asshole.
‫أرني ما لديك يا حقير.‬
Sang-min, please stop.
‫توقّف يا "سانغ مين"، أرجوك.‬
Just shut your mouth and come at me, asshole.
‫أطبق فمك وقاتلني يا وغد!‬
You aren't going to fight back? Why?
‫ألن تقاتلني؟ لماذا؟‬
Because you can't hit a cripple?
‫ألأنك لا تستطيع أن تضرب معوّقًا؟‬
Hit me!
‫اضربني!‬
You've always looked down on me, haven't you?
‫لطالما ازدريتني.‬
And your damn son made me a cripple!
‫وابنك اللعين أصابني بإعاقة!‬
You bastard!
‫أيها السافل!‬
I'm sorry, Sang-min.
‫أنا آسف يا "سانغ مين".‬
I'm sorry.
‫أنا آسف.‬
Don't say that shit.
‫لا تقل هذا الكلام.‬
The more you apologize…
‫كلّما اعتذرت أكثر…‬
the more I feel like a total fool.
‫شعرت بأنني غبي أكثر.‬
My wife left me like that
‫هجرتني زوجتي ببساطة،‬
because I'm an idiot.
‫لأنني غبي.‬
You know very well how pathetic I am.
‫وأنت تعرف جيدًا كم إنني مثير للشفقة.‬
But why are you looking at me with pity in your eyes?
‫لكن لماذا أرى الشفقة في نظرتك إليّ؟‬
Fuck, that makes me feel even more pathetic.
‫بئسًا! هذا يجعلني أشعر‬ ‫بأنني مثير للشفقة أكثر.‬
No, Sang-min.
‫لا يا "سانغ مين".‬
Everything that's happened to you and my son is my fault.
‫كلّ ما حصل لك ولابني هو ذنبي.‬
When my wife collapsed…
‫حين انهارت زوجتي…‬
I had no idea because I was too bent on catching perps.
‫لم أعرف لأنني كنت أركّز حصرًا‬ ‫على القبض على المجرمين.‬
-She died. -How could this happen?
‫- لقد ماتت.‬ ‫- كيف أمكن حدوث ذلك؟‬
She was such a kind person.
‫كانت إنسانة طيبة.‬
-But she did seem a bit weak. -What is going on?
‫- لكنها بدت ضعيفة بعض الشيء.‬ ‫- ماذا يجري؟‬
Maybe that's why.
‫ربما هذا هو السبب.‬
I feel so bad for them!
‫أنا أشفق عليهم!‬
Are you the husband?
‫هل أنت الزوج؟‬
She went into hypoglycemic shock.
‫أُصيبت بانخفاض في سكر الدم.‬
Your son had headphones on in his room, so she was found too late.
‫كان ابنك يضع سماعات في غرفته،‬ ‫لذا تم العثور عليها بعد فوات الأوان.‬
What were you doing?
‫ماذا كنت تفعل؟‬
What the hell were you doing?
‫ماذا الذي كنت تفعله؟‬
It was an accident.
‫كان ذلك حادثًا.‬
It wasn't Jun-hyung's fault.
‫لم يكن ذلك خطأ "جون هيونغ".‬
But I found myself blurting out those words.
‫لكنني نطقت بتلك الكلمات فجأة.‬
He was already blaming himself for it.
‫كان يلوم نفسه على ما حصل أساسًا.‬
I shouldn't have said such a thing.
‫ما كان يجب أن أقول ذاك الكلام.‬
I thought he would realize over time that I didn't mean what I said.
‫ظننت أنه سيدرك مع الوقت‬ ‫أنني لم أقصد ما قلته.‬
Because we're family.
‫لأننا عائلة.‬
But I was wrong.
‫لكنني كنت مخطئًا.‬
Had I corrected it then and there, you wouldn't have ended up like this.
‫لو أنني صححت الموقف في حينها،‬ ‫لما حصل لك هذا.‬
Yes, Dae-su.
‫نعم يا "دايسو".‬
Sir, we found Kim Young-ho's car.
‫سيدي، وجدنا سيارة "يونغ هو كيم".‬
Yeah?
‫وبعد؟‬
We tracked him down using security camera footage,
‫تعقبناه باستخدام كاميرات المراقبة،‬
but its windows are shattered, and we can't find him.
‫لكن زجاج السيارة محطم‬ ‫ولا نستطيع العثور عليه.‬
What?
‫ماذا؟‬
Check the nearby cameras first. Call me if you find any suspicious cars.
‫تحقق من الكاميرات القريبة أولًا.‬ ‫اتصل بي إن وجدت أي سيارات مشبوهة.‬
-Yes, sir. -What about Yoon Seo-ha?
‫- نعم يا سيدي.‬ ‫- ماذا عن "سو ها يون"؟‬
We haven't found her yet.
‫لم نجدها بعد.‬
She's not at home, but we'll contact you as soon as we find her.
‫ليست في البيت،‬ ‫لكننا سنتصل بك بمجرد أن نجدها.‬
Okay.
‫حسنًا.‬
I got a call from the autopsy room.
‫اتصلوا بي من المشرحة.‬
Its owner is Kim's maternal relative and also Yoon's paternal relative.
‫صاحب الحمض النووي هو قريب "كيم"‬ ‫من جهة الأم وقريب "يون" من جهة الأب.‬
A woman with type A blood.
‫امرأة زمرة دمها "ألف".‬
DNA matching Kim Young-ho's maternal side and Yoon Seo-ha's paternal side?
‫حمض نووي لقريب "كيم" من جهة أمه‬ ‫ولقريب "يون" من جهة أبيها؟‬
What does that mean?
‫ماذا يعني ذلك؟‬
I'm not sure, but I think Kim Young-ho's mother is definitely alive.
‫لست متأكدًا، لكن أظن‬ ‫أن والدة "يونغ هو كيم" حية بالتأكيد.‬
We must find her.
‫يجب أن نجدها.‬
Hey, wait a minute.
‫مهلًا، انتظر لحظة.‬
Yes, sir.
‫نعم يا سيدي.‬
Do you have the info on the person who was close to Yoon Myung-gil's family?
‫هل لديك المعلومات عن الشخص‬ ‫الذي كان مقربًا من عائلة "ميونغ غيل يون"؟‬
Yes, do you mean the neighbor who knew the family well since they were young?
‫نعم، هل تقصد الجارة‬ ‫التي تعرف العائلة جيدًا منذ الصغر؟‬
Yeah, that one.
‫نعم.‬
Text me the address of that person now.
‫أرسل لي العنوان الآن.‬
Will do, sir.
‫حاضر يا سيدي.‬
Let's go.
‫لنذهب.‬
PARKING LOT
‫"موقف سيارات"‬
The person we're meeting now seems to have lived
‫يبدو أن المرأة التي سنقابلها الآن عاشت‬
where Yoon Myung-ho's family lived when they were young.
‫حيث عاشت عائلة "ميونغ هو يون" في الصغر.‬
We need to find the woman Yoon Myung-ho chose over his daughter.
‫يجب أن نجد المرأة‬ ‫التي فضّلها "ميونغ هو يون" على ابنته.‬
That's Kim Young-ho's mother.
‫هذه والدة "يونغ هو كيم".‬
This series of incidents happened right after Yoon Myung-gil died.
‫وقعت هذه الحوادث بعد موت "ميونغ غيل يون".‬
The culprit must be
‫لا بد أن القاتل‬
a relative with a connection to the burial ground.
‫هو قريب له علاقة بأرض المدافن.‬
Tell me where your boss is.
‫أخبرني أين رئيسك.‬
I told you that we don't know either.
‫أخبرتك أننا لا نعرف أيضًا.‬
Seriously, why do you keep asking that?
‫لماذا تستمرين بطرح هذا السؤال؟‬
You work here. You must've called him if he didn't show up for work.
‫أنت تعمل هنا. لا بد أنك اتصلت به‬ ‫إن لم يأت إلى العمل.‬
I told you that he hasn't contacted us.
‫أخبرتك أنه لم يتصل بنا.‬
Seriously.
‫جديًا.‬
Stop bothering us and leave, okay?
‫كفي عن إزعاجنا وغادري، اتفقنا؟‬
You can go outside and contact him or look for him for all I care!
‫اخرجي واتصلي به أو فلتبحثي عنه، لا يهمني!‬
Ma'am.
‫سيدتي.‬
You're dripping water on the floor. Ma'am.
‫أنت تقطرين الماء على الأرض. سيدتي.‬
At least give me a tip before you ask! Ma'am.
‫أقلّه أعطيني بقشيشًا قبل أن تسألي! سيدتي!‬
What a jerk.
‫يا له من أحمق.‬
YUJIN MEATS
‫"(يوجين) للحوم"‬
Myung-ho was the oldest brother.
‫كان "ميونغ هو" الأخ الأكبر.‬
After him was Myung-gil, and then there was the youngest sister.
‫بعده يأتي "ميونغ غيل" وبعده الأخت الصغرى.‬
Myung-ho wasn't that crazy, you know.
‫لم يكن "ميونغ هو" مجنونًا لهذه الدرجة.‬
That's a bit different from what I heard.
‫هذا لا يطابق ما سمعته.‬
I heard the eldest was completely insane,
‫سمعت أن الابن الأكبر سنًا كان مجنونًا كليًا،‬
which was why the second son, Myung-gil, inherited the family burial ground.
‫ولهذا السبب، ورث الابن الثاني أرض المدافن.‬
I feel uncomfortable
‫أشعر بعدم الارتياح‬
talking to a stranger about another family's matters.
‫لتحدّثي إلى شخص غريب عن مشاكل عائلة أخرى.‬
It's a rumor, after all.
‫إنها شائعة في النهاية.‬
This is a murder case.
‫هذه جريمة قتل.‬
Rumor or not, you should tell us what you know.
‫أشائعة كانت أم لا،‬ ‫يجب أن تخبرينا ما تعرفينه.‬
Well,
‫في الواقع،‬
Myung-ho really cared a lot for his younger sister.
‫كان "ميونغ هو" يهتم كثيرًا‬ ‫لأمر أخته الصغرى.‬
He treasured her very much.
‫كان يعزّها كثيرًا.‬
Myung-hee was often teased by other kids,
‫كانت "ميونغ هي" تتعرض دائمًا للتنمّر‬ ‫من الأطفال الآخرين،‬
and Myung-ho always protected her.
‫وكان "ميونغ هو" يحميها دائمًا.‬
That's right.
‫هذا صحيح.‬
Kids her age used to tease her a lot ever since she was little.
‫كان الأطفال في مثل سنّها يعاكسونها كثيرًا‬ ‫منذ طفولتها.‬
She also cried a lot over little things.
‫وكانت تبكي كثيرًا بسبب أمور تافهة.‬
Children naturally feel like
‫بطبيعة الحال، يشعر الأطفال‬
the world is ending even over small things.
‫بأن العالم سينتهي بسبب مسائل بسيطة.‬
Even so, she cried all the time!
‫مع ذلك، كانت تبكي طوال الوقت!‬
That's why Myung-ho stayed right by her even after she grew up.
‫لهذا السبب بقي "ميونغ هو" بجانبها،‬ ‫حتى بعد أن كبرت.‬
They were so close that everyone in the neighborhood knew the two of them.
‫كانا مقربين جدًا‬ ‫لدرجة أن كلّ من في الحي كان يعرفهما.‬
But then, they suddenly disappeared.
‫لكن فجأة، اختفى الاثنان.‬
By that, do you mean
‫وبهذا الكلام، هل تقصدين‬
the two of them died at that time?
‫أنهما ماتا في الوقت نفسه؟‬
No, they didn't pass away. They probably got kicked out of the house.
‫لا، لم يموتا. لا بد أنهما طُردا من البيت.‬
Because when they left,
‫لأنهما حين غادرا،‬
Myung-hee's belly was big.
‫كان بطن "ميونغ هي" كبيرًا جدًا.‬
She was pregnant?
‫هل كانت حاملًا؟‬
Yes, pregnant!
‫نعم، حامل!‬
and that was why Myung-ho's father kicked them out.
‫ولهذا السبب طردهما أب "ميونغ هو".‬
Goodness, I told you that's not true!
‫عجبًا! قلت لك إن هذا ليس صحيحًا!‬
They were siblings.
‫كانا أخوين.‬
Of course it's true.
‫طبعًا هذا صحيح.‬
Why else would Myung-ho have vanished right when Myung-hee disappeared?
‫وإلّا لم اختفى "ميونغ هو"‬ ‫بمجرد أن اختفت "ميونغ هي"؟‬
And someone saw them run away in the middle of the night.
‫ورآهما أحدهم يهربان معًا في منتصف الليل.‬
Did anyone see the two of them running away at that time?
‫هل رآهما أحد يهربان في ذاك الوقت؟‬
Yes. The old barber down the road said he had seen them.
‫نعم. قال الحلّاق الذي يعمل في نهاية الطريق‬ ‫إنه رآهما.‬
And that's not all.
‫وهذا ليس كلّ شيء.‬
About three or four years after that,
‫بعد نحو ثلاث أو أربع سنوات،‬
word got around
‫حُكي‬
that someone saw them living together in another neighborhood.
‫أن أحدهم رآهما يعيشان معًا في حي آخر.‬
Come on now!
‫بحقك!‬
What's wrong with siblings living together after they leave their parents?
‫ما العيب إن عاش أخوان معًا‬ ‫بعد تركهما بيت العائلة؟‬
Nonsense.
‫هذا هراء.‬
Girl, it makes no sense that the jerk
‫يا فتاة! من غير المنطقي أن الحقير‬
who had abandoned his wife and kid was just living with his sister.
‫الذي تخلّى عن زوجته وابنته‬ ‫كان يعيش مع أخته.‬
And someone saw Myung-hee carrying a three-year-old child
‫ورأى أحدهم "ميونغ هي"‬ ‫تحمل طفلًا في الثالثة من عمره‬
with Myung-ho by their side.
‫وكان "ميونغ هو" يقف معهما.‬
Kim Young-ho, Yoon Seo-ha, and the source of this blood,
‫"يونغ هو كيم" و"سو ها يون" ومصدر هذا الدم،‬
their paternal lineage all match up.
‫النسب الأبوي مطابق.‬
This person is Kim's maternal relative and also Yoon Seo-ha's paternal relative.
‫هذا الشخص قريب "كيم" من جهة الأم‬ ‫وقريب "يون" من جهة الأب.‬
They also heard that child calling Myung-ho "Daddy."
‫كما أنهم سمعوا الطفل‬ ‫ينادي "ميونغ هو" بـ"أبي".‬
Are you saying that Ms. Yoon Myung-hee had a child with her biological brother?
‫هل تقصدين أن الآنسة "ميونغ هي يون"‬ ‫أنجبت طفلًا من أخيها الحقيقي؟‬
I'm almost certain of it.
‫أنا شبه متأكدة من ذلك.‬
They had a child together in incest.
‫أنجبا طفلًا ثمرة سفاح القربى.‬
WOLGUNGJANG MOTEL
‫"نزل (ولغانغجانغ)"‬
Please leave a mes--
‫اتركوا رسالة…‬
Shit! Are you kidding me?
‫تبًا! غير معقول!‬
But not too long after that rumor went around,
‫لكن بعد وقت قصير من انتشار تلك الشائعة،‬
Myung-ho returned home.
‫عاد "ميونغ هو" إلى البيت.‬
From then on, so many shamans kept going in and out of that house.
‫ومنذ ذلك الحين، زار شامانات كثر ذاك البيت.‬
You bastard!
‫أيها السافل!‬
There is a ghost clinging to your back, committing evil deeds with your body.
‫ثمة شبح يتشبث بظهرك‬ ‫ويرتكب أفعالًا شريرة بجسدك.‬
They said Myung-ho became like that because of an evil spirit attached to him,
‫قالوا إن "ميونغ هو" أصبح كما هو عليه‬ ‫لأن روحًا شريرة تعلّقت به،‬
so they kept performing the ritual on him even though he was totally fine.
‫واستمروا بممارسة طقوس عليه‬ ‫مع أنه كان بخير حال.‬
Meanwhile, Myung-hee took her child to stay at a strange temple.
‫في هذه الأثناء، أخذت "ميونغ هي" طفلها‬ ‫لتقيم في معبد غريب.‬
Gyeongamsa Temple?
‫معبد "جيونغامسا"؟‬
That's right! Gyeongamsa.
‫هذا صحيح! "جيونغامسا".‬
It was a temple where Buddhist monks practiced shamanism.
‫كان معبدًا‬ ‫يمارس فيه الرهبان البوذيون الشامانية.‬
Why did she go to that temple?
‫لماذا ذهبت إلى ذاك المعبد؟‬
Without Myung-ho, it was hard for her to live in peace.
‫من دون "ميونغ هو"،‬ ‫كان من الصعب عليها أن تعيش في سلام.‬
I heard she had gone into hiding with her child to live away from people.
‫سمعت أنها اختبأت مع طفلها‬ ‫لتعيش بعيدًا عن الناس.‬
Apparently, her plan was to make a living through shamanism,
‫يبدو أنها كانت تنوي‬ ‫أن تكسب عيشها من خلال الشامانية،‬
so she lied that her child had the divine illness when he didn't.
‫فكذبت قائلة إن طفلها مسّته "الريح الإلهية"‬ ‫لكنه لم يكن كذلك.‬
Besides, your son doesn't have the divine illness.
‫كما أن ابنك لم تمسّه "الريح الإلهية".‬
Son? My son? You mean Kim Young-ho?
‫ابن؟ ابني؟ أتقصدين "يونغ هو كيم"؟‬
Dear me. If people had found out her child was a product of incest,
‫يا ويلي! إن عرف الناس‬ ‫أن طفلها ثمرة علاقة سفاح القربى،‬
they would've judged them so harshly.
‫لحكموا عليهما بقسوة.‬
I bet she wanted to hide from people as best as she could.
‫أراهن أنها أرادت أن تختبئ من الناس‬ ‫قدر استطاعتها.‬
What was that?
‫ما كان ذلك؟‬
Shit!
‫تبًا!‬
Come on!
‫هيا!‬
Even their own family turned their backs on them.
‫حتى عائلتهما تخلت عنهما.‬
Myung-hee probably wanted to stay out of sight for her child's sake
‫أرادت "ميونغ هي" على الأرجح‬ ‫أن تتوارى عن الأنظار من أجل طفلها،‬
and live like she didn't even exist.
‫وتعيش كأنه لم يكن لها وجود.‬
Damn it. How did it get stuck in there?
‫تبًا! كيف علق هذا هناك؟‬
Why was Ms. Yoon Myung-hee teased by others when she was young?
‫لماذا كانت الآنسة "ميونغ هي يون"‬ ‫تتعرض للتنمر في صغرها؟‬
Cleft palate.
‫بسبب الشفة المشقوقة.‬
She was born with a cleft palate,
‫وُلدت بشفة مشقوقة،‬
but she got the surgery too late, so the other kids teased her a lot.
‫لكنها خضعت للجراحة بعد فوات الأوان،‬ ‫ولذلك تعرضت للكثير من التنمر.‬
But who are you, ma'am?
‫لكن من أنت يا سيدتي؟‬
I heard that Mr. Yoon lived alone.
‫سمعت أن السيد "يون" كان يعيش بمفرده.‬
I'm a local resident.
‫أنا من السكان المحليين.‬
Are you close with Mr. Yoon?
‫هل أنت مقربة من السيد "يون"؟‬
Well, he's just a neighborhood friend.
‫إنه مجرد صديق في الحي.‬
It seems Mr. Yoon has no family.
‫يبدو أنه ليس للسيد "يون" عائلة.‬
Well…
‫في الواقع…‬
How long has he been living on his own?
‫منذ متى يعيش بمفرده؟‬
Oh, he had an older brother.
‫كان لديه أخ أكبر سنًا.‬
A crazy guy, but I heard he died.
‫رجل مجنون، لكنني سمعت أنه مات.‬
I have just as much of a right to my uncle's burial ground as she does!
‫يحق لي بأرض مدافن عمي بقدرها!‬
Let me go, you bastard!
‫اتركني يا وغد!‬
Subtitle translation by Daham Yoon
‫ترجمة "موريال ضو"‬